Finding aid for the Karl G. Yoneda papers, 1892-1998, bulk 1925-1989 LSC.1592
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 4. Manuscripts, Publications, and Lectures, 1923-1994
  - 4.3 Lectures and Talks by Yoneda, 1969-1989
    - Evacuation and Camp Experience, 1971 January 29-1988 February 7 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      Transcripts of Yoneda's lectures. Titles include: "U.S. Concentration Camps"; "Evacuation Experiences"; "Concentration Camp Experience: Loyalty Issue, the Other Side"; "Evacuation: Why?"; "Our Concentration Camp Experiences"; "Japanese American and Concentration Camps"; and "Pearl Harbor and Manzanar."
    - Racism and Evacuation, 1970 January 27-1975 March 31 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      Transcripts of Yoneda's lectures. Titles of his lectures include: "Racism and Its Relation to Evacuation"; "Evacuation and Racism"; and "Racism and Evacuation."
    - Racism, 1969 July 10-1971 October 13 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      Transcripts of Yoneda's lectures. Titles include: "Racism and Our Yellow Heritage"; and "Racism and It's Relationship to Militarism."
    - Autobiography, 1984 August 31-1992 May 30 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      Transcripts of Yoneda's talks. His talks were given at Association for Asian American Studies; and Japanese American Historical Society of Southern California Meeting, Torrance, California.
    - Labor Organizing Experiences, 1979 February 10 (Box 25, Folder 11)
      Transcripts of Yoneda's lecture titled as: My Labor Organizing Experiences.
    - Asian/Pacific Pioneers, 1984 April 19 (Box 25, Folder 12)
      Transcripts of Yoneda's talk titled as: A Tribute to Asian/Pacific Pioneers.
    - Asian/Pacific Immigration, 1980 December 12-13 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      Transcripts of Yoneda's talk given at a conference on Asian/Pacific immigration, University of Southern California, on December 13, 1980. Also includes the conference brochures and pamphlets, a news clipping, and correspondence.
    - Asian/Pacific Workers and US Labor Movement, 1987 November 12-15 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      Transcripts of Yoneda's talk given at West Coast Marxist Scholars Conference, UC Berkeley, December 12-15, 1987. Also includes the conference brochure.
    - Comments on Papers, 1978 May 5, 1980 April 10 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      Transcripts of Yoneda's comments on Yuji Ichioka's paper, "Asian Coal Miners and the UMWA" delivered at Asian American Labor History Conference, UC Los Angeles on May 5, 1978, along with the conference brochures, correspondence, and other materials.
    - San Francisco Bay Area Labor Workshop, 1979 July 30, 1984 November 18 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      Transcripts of Yoneda's talk, "Organizing Alaska Cannery Workers", given at the San Francisco Bay Area Labor Workshop, on November 18, 1984. Also includes correspondence from Prof. Donald L. Guimary, Dept. of Journalism, Portland State University.
    - Communist Party, USA Events, 1972-1985 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      Transcripts of Yoneda's talk given at various events for the Communist Party, USA. Titles include: "Asian Labor in the USA"; "Asians and Pacific Islanders"; "Anti- Fascism: World War II"; "62nd Anniversary Celebration of the CPUSA"; "Asian Pacific Americans and CPUSA"; "Asian Pacific Island Americans and CPUSA"; "The Asian/Pacific Island American Question"; "Racism and Black Liberation"; "Our Trip to Koyagi (Near Nagasaki)"; and "CPUSA and Its Relation with Japanese Americans Including WWII."
    - American Issues Forum of San Francisco, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      Questionnaire and Yoneda's answer for the symposium at the forum. Also includes a brochure, a pamphlet, and correspondence.
    - Southwest Labor Studies Association Annual Conferences, 1980, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      Transcripts of Yoneda's talks given at the 6th and 11th annual conferences of the Southwest Labor Studies Association, correspondence, and brochures. Titles include: "Japanese Radicals and Laborites in the San Francisco Bay Area from 19875 to 1925"; and "Organizing Alaska Cannery Workers."
    - The Nisei and the Japanese Immigrant Press Symposium, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      Transcripts of Yoneda's talks given at the Nisei and the Japanese Immigrant Press International Conference, "Coming of Age in the Thirties", at the Japanese American Cultural and Community Center, Los Angeles, California, September 14-15, 1985. Titles include: "Radical Nikkei Press During the '20s and '30s"; and his comments on Professor Norio Tamura's paper, titled as: Japan and the Japanese American Leftist Press. Also includes correspondence, the conference brochures, and news clippings.
    - Japan Visit, 1972 September 29 (Box 26, Folder 7)
      Transcripts of Yoneda's talk on his Japan trip when attending the international symposium, "Problems of Revolutionary Movements in Developed Capitalist Countries" sponsored by the Japanese Communist Party for its 50th anniversary celebration, given at the Pine United Methodist Church, San Francisco, California, on September 29, 1972.
    - Other Talks, 1971-1989 (Box 26, Folder 8)
      Transcripts of Yoneda's talks given at various occasions, including the 14th anniversary of the People's World; the Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians; the Meiklejohn Civil Liberties Institute Symposium; a buffet dinner, "A Salute to Asian/Pacific American Labor"; the Stonewall Gay Democratic Club; the Stonestown YMCA Senior Club; and others. Titles include: "San Francisco's Asians"; "The Right to Earn a Living in the U.S.: Yesterday and Tomorrow"; "A Benefit for Asian/Pacific American Federation of Union Members"; "Evacuation of Japanese Americans During WWII and Pending Voting on Prop 64"; "Japanese American Aleut Evacuation and Redress/Reparation Campaign"; "The July 5th Bloody Thursday"; and "Meaning of Hiroshima and Nagasaki."
    - Lecture Audiotape, 1969 February 25 (Box 26, Folder 9)
      An audiotape of Yoneda's lecture given at 100X class, Asian American Studies, UC Berkeley.
    - Marxist Study Series, 1974-1984 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      Programs of the Marxist Study Series including Yoneda's lectures.
    - Programs, 1969-1982, undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
      Brochures, announcements, correspondence, and news clippings regarding Yoneda's lectures and talks given at various programs.
  - 4.4 Manuscripts and Publications by Others, 1972-1994
    Contains manuscripts and publications forwarded from individual authors to Yoneda. Correspondence from the authors, Yoneda's comments, and news clippings, are also included. Files are listed by the authors' names in alphabetical order.
    - Doug Forester and Joan Zoloth, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      Photocopies of: "Like Outlaws, Like Thieves: How 'Illegal Aliens' Take the Rap for Our Economic Problems." Mother Jones (Apr. 1976): 11-17.
    - Friday, Chris, 1984-1985 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      Two papers written by Chris Friday. "Huagong Amongst the Salmon: A Preliminary Study of the Chinese in the Salmon Canning Industry, from the Mouth of the Columbia River to the Cascades, 1870-1910"; and "Asian Contractors and Contract Labor on the Columbia River 1870-1910."
    - Glenn, Evelyn Nakano, 1980-1981 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      Photocopies of two articles written by Glenn, Evelyn Nakano. "The Dialectics of Wage Work: Japanese-American Women and Domestic Service, 1905-1940." Feminist Studies vol. 6 no. 3 (Fall 1980): 432-471; and "Occupational Ghettoization: Japanese American Women and Domestic service, 1905-1970." Ethnicity 8 (1981).
    - Hanawa, Yukiko, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 6)
      A paper written by Yukiko Hanawa, "Issei Women: Some Preliminary Observations."
    - Hansen, Arthur A., 1994 (Box 27, Folder 7)
      Hansen, Arthur A., "A Riot of Voices: Racial and Ethnic Variables in Interactive Oral History Interviewing," in "Interactive Oral History Interviewing", ed. Eva M. McMahan et al. (New Jersey: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, 1944), 107-139.
    - Arthur A. Hansen and David A. Hacker, 1974-1977 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      Manuscripts of: "The Manzanar 'Riot': An Ethnic Perspective," written by Arthur A. Hansen and David A. Hacker; and its published article in: Amerasia Journal vol. 2 no. 2 (Fall 1974): 112-157.
    - Harrington, Joseph H., 1977-1982 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      Interview transcripts of Yoneda for Joseph H. Harrington's publication, "Yankee Samurai."
    - Ichioka, Yuji (1 of 4), 1976-1980 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      A preliminary draft of Yuji Ichioka's article, "Ameyuki-san: Japanese Prostitutes in 19th Century America," and its published article in: Pacific Historical Rreview vol. 49 no. 2 (May 1980): 339-357.
    - Ichioka, Yuji (2 of 4), 1977 (Box 27, Folder 11)
      Manuscripts of: "Japanese Immigrant Labor Contractors and the Northern Pacific and the Great Northern Railroad Companies, 1898-1907"; and its published article in: Labor History vol. 21 no. 3 (Summer 1980): 325-350.
    - Ichioka, Yuji (3 of 4), 1978-1979 (Box 27, Folder 12)
      Ichioka, Yuji, "Asian Immigrant Coal Miners and the United Mine Workers of America: Race and Class at Rock Springs, Wyoming, 1907." Amerasia 6:2 (1979): 1-23. Also includes photocopies of letters regarding Japanese coal miners.
    - Ichioka, Yuji (4 of 4), 1979 (Box 27, Folder 13)
      Manuscripts of: "Private Japanese Diplomacy: Suzuki Bunji, Organized American Labor, and Japanese Immigrant Workers, 1915-1916" written by Yuji Ichioka.
    - Larson, Ronald C., 1973 (Box 27, Folder 14)
      Manuscripts of: "Doho: the Communist Japanese American Press 1938- 1942" written by Ronald C. Larson. Includes a photograph of Kazumaro Buddy Uno and other JACL leaders with a message from Arthur Hansen and Ron Larson to Yoneda.
    - Magnus, Randy, circa 1991 (Box 27, Folder 15)
      A VHS tape, "Ganbatte: 60 Year Struggle of Karl Yoneda," by Randy Magnus.
    - Mitson, Betty E., 1974-1979 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      Manuscripts of: "Looking Back in Anguish: Oral History and Japanese- American Evacuation"; and its published article in: "The Oral History Review" (1974): 24-51.
    - Sawada, Noriko, circa 1979 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      Manuscripts of: "Mother: an Autobiographical Story" written by Noriko Sawada.
    - Schonberger, Howard, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      Schonberger, Howard, "Dilemmas of Loyalty: Japanese Americans and the Psychological Warfare Campaigns of the Office of Strategic Services, 1943-45." Amerasia 16:1 (1990): 20-38.
    - Shibata, Etsuko, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      ???? Shibata, Etsuko, "????????????????: ?????????????? ILWU??? Hyaku-sanjurokunichikan no Fukutsu no Kowan Sutoraiki: Kontena-ka ni Yoru "Gorika" to ILWU no Toso." Gendai no Rodo Kumiai Undo (1972): 256-284.
    - Sohner, Charles, circa 1983 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      Sohner, Charles. Power in Transition: Labor's Political Influence. Huntington Beach: American Studies Publishing Company, c1983.
    - Tamura, Norio, 1984-1989 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      Articles by Norio Tamura published in various issues of "???????? ? Nikkei Shinbun Kenkyu Noto," and "???????????? Zaibei Nikkei Shinbun no Hattatsushi Kenkyu." Also includes one issue of "??????? Imin Kenkyukai Kaiho."
    - Tanaka, Michiko, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      ????? Tanaka, Michiko. "???????? Shisuko no Fujinde." Fujin Tsushin (May 1981): 34-36.
- 5. Japanese American/Canadian Redress and Reparations, 1971-1992
  Series comprises materials regarding Japanese American/Canadian redress and reparations. Contains testimonies of Karl and Elaine Yoneda and other Japanese American individuals and related materials to the Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians Hearings, including letters, Yoneda's writings, materials issued by U.S. government agencies and other organizations, and news clippings. There is also a folder containing materials regarding Canadian American redress.
  - 5.1 Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians Hearings, 1981
    Materials regarding Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians Hearings, held in Los Angeles, San Francisco, and Chicago in 1981. Includes testimonies of Karl and Elaine Yoneda and other Japanese American individuals to testify against the U.S. government.
    - Los Angeles Hearing on August 5, 1981, and San Francisco Hearing on August 11-12, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      Contains a list of the commissioners and the hearing schedule; a photograph of Yoneda attending the hearing in San Francisco; agendas for the hearings held in Los Angeles and San Francisco in 1981, listing Japanese Americans individuals who testify against the US government; testimony of Yoneda and other witnesses; correspondence; Yoneda's manuscripts for news articles, describing the hearings; camp documents; and news clippings. Also includes photocopies of "Euphemistic and Accurate Terminology" by Raymond Y. Okamura, prepared for the Japanese American Citizens League National Committee for Redress for Presentation to the Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians.
    - Elaine Yoneda's Testimony, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 9)
      Documents regarding Elaine Yoneda's testimony. Contains instructional materials for the testimony prepared by the JACL, including a question and answer fact sheet on the Commission, and guidelines and examples for testimony; correspondence; drafts of Elaine Yoneda's testimony; testimonies of other individuals; and news clippings.
    - Testimonies for Hearings in San Francisco, 1981 August 11-13 (Box 28, Folder 10)
      Photocopies of documents including, written testimonies by Japanese American individuals and a historian, and a memorandum by the Bay Area Attorneys for Redress attached to John Franklin Carter's summary of the Munson's Report and a report on the West Coast Japanese Americans by Curtis B. Munson.
    - Chicago Hearings, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 11)
      Documents issued by the National Council for Japanese American Redress after the Chicago hearings of the CWRIC on September 23, 1981, photocopies of the testimony of Rev. Martin Deppeand, and camp materials.
  - 5.2 Materials Related to Japanese American Redress and Reparations, 1975-1992
    Contains letters, Yoneda's writings, copies of documents issued by the U.S. government agencies, materials issued by various organizations and groups to support and pursue the Japanese American redress and reparation, fliers for the Days of Remembrance; news clippings regarding Japanese American Redress and Reparations collected between 1975 and 1992, Samuel Ichie Hayakawa, and Frank Chin.
    - Drafts and Resolutions, 1981-1990 (Box 28, Folder 12)
      Letters; a draft of a paper, "Redress for 9066," by Linda Walsh; drafts of Yoneda's comments sent to editors; drafts of "Resolution," "Resolution on Illegal Internment of Japanese Americans and Aleuts during WWII," and "Resolution against Confirmation of Bork to the U.S. Supreme Court;" and handwritten letters by John Edgar Hoover.
    - Government Documents, 1980-1990 (Box 28, Folder 13)
      Copies of documents issued by U.S. government agencies, including Congressional records of the 97th 2nd session, the 98th 1st session, and the 99th 1st session, a booklet, "Redress Regulations: Questions and Answers," correspondence, and photocopies of $20,000 reparations check. Also includes two original letters sent from the Office of the Vice President.
    - International Longshoremen's & Warehousemen's Union, 1979-1988 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      Copies of "Resolution on Redress/Reparations for Japanese Americans" delivered at the 23rd ILWU Biennial Convention, "Resolution on Reparations for Japanese- American and Aleutian Victims of Wartime Internment" at the 27 ILWU Convention, Yoneda's writings of "Resolution" submitted to ILWU, and the 27th ILWU convention materials.
    - Japanese American Citizens League (JACL), 1978-1990 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      Materials issued by JACL. Includes pamphlets of "The Japanese American Incarceration: A Case for Redress," 1st, 2nd, and 3rd ed., published between 1978 and 1980, with Yoneda's comments on 1st edition; a booklet, "Personal Justice Denied: Summary and Recommendations of the Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians"; photocopies of "Redress Question and Answer Fact Sheet"; some issues of "The Redress Monitor"; announcements; brochures; and news clippings.
    - National Alliance Against Racist & Political Repression (NAARPR), 1981 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      Materials from the 6th conference of the NAARPR in 1981. Includes "Resolution on Illegal Internment of Japanese Americans and Aleuts during WWII" submitted by Yoneda.
    - National Coalition for Redress/Reparations (NCRR), 1980-1990 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      Materials issued by NCRR, including brochures, a bulletin, and announcements.
    - National Coalition for Japanese American Redress (NCJAR), 1979-1986 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      Announcements and newsletters issued by NCJAR. Includes photocopies of Yoneda's remarks, "Proposition 64," given to the Stonewall Gay Democratic Club on October 6, 1986, talking about evacuation of Japanese Americans during WWII and pending voting on Prop 84.
    - Day of Remembrance, 1979-1988 (Box 29, Folder 6)
      Fliers for the Days of Remembrance. Also includes materials on Tanforan Detention Center issued by the Tanforan Committee.
    - Programs, 1979-1981 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      Programs and event announcements organized by various groups.
    - News Clippings (1 of 10), 1975-1979 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - News Clippings (2 of 10), 1980 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - News Clippings (3 of 10), 1981 January-July (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - News Clippings (4 of 10), 1981 August (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - News Clippings (5 of 10), 1981 September-December (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - News Clippings (6 of 10), 1982 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - News Clippings (7 of 10), 1983-1984 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - News Clippings (8 of 10), 1985-1987 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - News Clippings (9 of 10), 1988-1989 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - News Clippings (10 of 10), 1990, 1992 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Pacific Citizen. Los Angeles, California, 1981 July 24-1982 Oct 22 (Box 31, Folder 1)
      Pacific Citizen. Los Angeles: Japanese American Citizens League. Uncut issues featuring the Japanese American redress and reparations.
    - News Clippings: S. I. Hayakawa, 1976-1984 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      News clippings on Samuel Ichiye Hayakawa's opposition against the redress of Japanese Americans.
    - News Clippings: Frank Chin, 1981 August-September (Box 31, Folder 3)
      Newspaper article, "A Circus of Freaks" by Frank Chin issued on Rafu Shimpo on August 21, 1981, describing the hearings of Japanese American witnesses and responses to his article.
  - 5.3 Canadian American Redress, 1971-1988
    Contains news clippings, brochures, and a pamphlet: "The exodus of the Japanese" by Janice Patton. Includes materials on the National Association of Japanese Canadians Redress Campaign.
    - Canadian American Redress, 1971-1988 (Box 31, Folder 4)
- 6. Investigation Case Files, 1941-1980
  Series comprised primarily of photocopies of the investigation case files for Yoneda held by U.S. government agencies, including the National Archives, the Department of Justice, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice, the Central Intelligence Agency, the Department of the Army, and the Department of the Air Force. There are missing pages withheld by the agencies.
  - Freedom of Information Act Request, 1978-1980 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    Correspondence, receipts for certified mail, and news clippings.
  - War Relocation Authority Evacuee Case Files, 1942-1943 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    Photocopies of documents obtained from the National Archives. Contains War Relocation Authority evacuee case files for Karl, Elaine, and Thomas Yoneda during their incarceration in the Manzanar War Relocation Center. Record Group 210.
  - Department of Justice, Federal Bureau of Investigation Files (1 of 7), 1941-1956 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    Photocopies of documents held by the Department of Justice, Federal Bureau of Investigation. Reference number: 100-19133-1 (April 10, 1941) to 100-19133-38 (January 27, 1956)
  - Department of Justice, Federal Bureau of Investigation Files (2 of 7), 1956 July 6-1962 April 2 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    Photocopies of documents held by the Department of Justice, Federal Bureau of Investigation. Reference number: 100-19133-40 (July 6, 1956) to 100-19133-87 (April 2, 1962).
  - Department of Justice, Federal Bureau of Investigation Files (3 of 7), 1962 April 23-1967 September 22 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    Photocopies of documents held by the Department of Justice, Federal Bureau of Investigation. Reference number: 100-19133-89 (April 23, 1962) to 122-3192-125 (September 22, 1967).
  - Department of Justice, Federal Bureau of Investigation Files (4 of 7), 1967 October 23-1974 January 23 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    Photocopies of documents held by the Department of Justice, Federal Bureau of Investigation. Reference number: 122-3192-126 (October 23, 1967) to 100- 19133-152 (January 23, 1974).
  - Department of Justice, Federal Bureau of Investigation Files (5 of 7), 1961 January 23-1962 April 24 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    Photocopies of documents held by the Department of Justice, Federal Bureau of Investigation. Reference number: 158-298-1 (January 23, 1961) to 158-298-15 (April 24, 1962).
  - Department of Justice, Federal Bureau of Investigation Files (6 of 7), 1962 April 27-1968 July 5 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    Photocopies of documents held by the Department of Justice, Federal Bureau of Investigation. Reference number: 158-298-16 (April 27, 1962) to 158-298-NR (July 5, 1968).
  - Department of Justice, Federal Bureau of Investigation Files (7 of 7), 1962 April 24-1967 July 24 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    Photocopies of documents held by the Department of Justice, Federal Bureau of Investigation. Reference number: 122-3192-1 (April 24, 1962) to 122-3192-2 (July 24, 1967).
  - Criminal Division of the Department of Justice and the Central Intelligence Agency, 1941 December 24-1968 June 25 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    Photocopies of documents forwarded by the Department of Justice, Federal Bureau of Investigation. The documents were held by the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice and the Central Intelligence Agency. Also includes letters from the Department of Justice Federal Bureau of Investigation. Reference number: 100-19133-15 (July 28, 1942); 100-19133-8 (December 24, 1941); 100-19133-84 (January 23, 1962); 158- 298-3 (April 11, 1961); 158-298-22 (July 30, 1962); 158-298-25 (September 13, 1962); 158- 298-31 (April 23, 1963); 158-298-14 (March 30, 1962); 158-298-NR (June 25, 1968); 100- 19133- 46 (December 2, 1959); 100-19133-54 (July 29, 1960); 100-19133-71 (February 28, 1961); 100-19133-71 (February 28, 1961); 100-19133-72 (April 5, 1961); 100-19133-87 (April 2, 1962).
  - Department of the Army, 1942 May 21-1968 July 3 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    Photocopies of documents forwarded by the Department of Justice, Federal Bureau of Investigation. The documents were held by the Department of Army. Also includes a letter from the Department of Justice Federal Bureau of Investigation. Reference number: 100- 19133- 14 (July 16, 1942); 100-19133-52 (July 8, 1960); 100-19133-62 (October 4, 1960); 100-19133-64 (October 21, 1960); 100-19133-66 (November 15, 1960); 100-19133-71 (February 28, 1961); 100-19133-71 (March 17, 1961); 100-19133-72 (April 5, 1961); 100-19133-96 (November 5, 1962); 100-19133-109 (March 29, 1965); 100-19133- 116 (July 28, 1965); 158-298-NR (July 3, 1968); 100-19133-13 (May 21, 1942); 100-19133- 52 (Doc. Nr.: 102160); 100-19133-64; 100-19133-65 (August 15, 1960); 100-19133-109 (March 4, 1965); 100-19133-116 (July 19, 1965).
  - Department of the Air Force, 1960 September 30 (Box 32, Folder 8)